O.J.: Made in America is a documentary, crime,
history film directed by Ezra Edelman.
A chronicle of the rise and fall of O.J.
Simpson, whose high-profile murder trial exposed the extent of American
racial tensions, revealing a fractured and divided nation.
Self (archive footage), played by O. J. Simpson.
Self (archive footage), played by Nicole Brown Simpson.
Self, played by Marcia Clark.
Self, played by Danny Bakewell Sr..
Self, played by F. Lee Bailey.
Self, played by Peter Hyams.
O.J.: Made in America is a 2016 American documentary, produced and directed
by Ezra Edelman for ESPN Films and their 30 for 30 series.
It was released as a five-part miniseries and in theatrical format.
O.J.: Made in America premiered at the Sundance Film Festival on January 22, 2016, and was theatrically
released in New York City and Los Angeles in May 2016 by Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures.
It debuted on ABC on June 11, 2016, and aired on ESPN.
The documentary explores race and celebrity through the life of O.
Simpson, from his emerging football career at the University of Southern California, and his celebrity and popularity within American culture, to his trial for the murders
of Nicole Brown Simpson and Ronald Lyle Goldman, and subsequent acquittal, and how he was convicted and imprisoned for the Las Vegas robbery 13 years later.
The documentary received critical acclaim and won the Academy Award for
Best Documentary Feature at the 89th Academy Awards.
It was the longest film in the 30 for 30 catalogue and longest film to ever
receive an Oscar nomination and win (surpassing War and Peace).
The documentary became the last of its type to be nominated and win an Oscar after a new Academy rule
barred any "multi-part or limited series" from being eligible for the documentary categories.
Edelman received the Primetime Emmy Award for Outstanding Directing for
Nonfiction Programming for his work on this project.
The series also received a Peabody Award for its work.
The film explores themes of police brutality, american football,
los angeles, california, true crime, racial tension.
The tone is dark.